My career in Information Technology started in 2002. I have created an Internet agency and conquered my first clients from door to door, offering services related to website development, technical support and web hosting. For twelve years, I have worked remotely on different types of projects for foreign companies, through outsourcing platforms.

In 2011, I launched a service that allowed any user to create their own "Google". The project was selected as a finalist in global Startup competitions. I had the opportunity to receive mentoring from FGV and support of the startup programs: FBStart from Facebook and AWS Activate for Startups. I was dedicated to the project for four years and it has ended after a few pivots. In the following years, I accepted new challenges at companies in different cities.

My mission is to create digital products based on quality and innovation. I seek to participate in projects that have meaning and deliver value to my clients. With the "feeling of ownership", I am interested in strategic positions related to IT and Innovation, with a focus on leadership and people management.

## **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL**

FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT

**VERSION CONTROL** 

MOBILE DEVELOPMENT

**DATABASES** 

SYSADMIN & DEVOPS

**PROTOTYPING** 

USER EXPERIENCE

#### **MANAGEMENT**

INNOVATIVE LEADERSHIP

**RECRUITMENT & SELECTION** 

**MENTORING & TRAINING** 

STRATEGIC PLANNING

**INTRAPRENEURSHIP** 

**COMMUNICATION & NEGOTIATION** 

AGILE METHODOLOGIES

## **EXPERIENCE**



Act Digital is an IT consultancy with a global presence. As a Technical Manager, my challenge is to align the interests of the company, the client and my team. I am assigned as an Engineering Team Lead for Moderna Therapeutics, a biotechnology company based in Cambridge, USA. I am responsible for interviewing candidates, onboarding new members and managing a team of developers in Brazil. I currently lead eleven people in four squads. In addition to monitoring their daily activities, I also provide feedback and one-on-one meetings, focusing on team satisfaction and engagement, and present reports to stakeholders.



REMOTE

Radix is a Great Place To Work® consultancy focused on engineering and technology in industrial sectors. I was allocated remotely in two clients: ChampionX and ONS, collaborating on CAPEX and OPEX projects. Supported multiple squads by managing backlogs, creating User Stories, designing and documenting UI/UX components. I followed and developed the IDP of interns and carried out In-Company training.



## **BRYNNER FERREIRA**

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER

Curitiba, Brazil 55 (41) 99676-0029 www.br7nner.com br7nner@gmail.com

## **EDUCATION**

# MANAGEMENT OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY AND COMMUNICATION

**JTFPR** 

GRADUATE SPECIALIZATION 2023

# DIGITAL BUSINESS: INNOVATION AND ENTREPRENEURSHIP

**PUCPR** 

GRADUATE SPECIALIZATION 2022

# SYSTEMS ANALYSIS AND DEVELOPMENT

**ESTÁCIO** 

ASSOCIATE'S DEGREE

### **PUBLICITY AND ADVERTISING**

FA7

BACHELOR'S DEGREE 2012

## **LANGUAGES**

**ENGLISH** 

INTERMEDIATE

PORTUGUESE

NATIVE

## **NETWORK**

- LINKEDIN GITHUB STACKOVERFLOW
- TWITTER MEDIUM TELEGRAM

### **EXPERIENCE**

# FRONT END MANAGER

TOTVS CURITIBA 2020 - 2021 TOTVS is the largest technology company in Brazil. One of its acquisitions was Exago, a European startup that offers B2B solutions for Innovation Management. I joined the team as technical leader and soon took over as Front End Manager. My activities are divided between bringing good market practices, optimizing the quality of deliveries, conducting Scrum ceremonies and monitoring activities.

# SYSTEMS ANALYST AND DEVELOPER

**GRUPO BOTICÁRIO**CURITIBA
2019 - 2020

Grupo Boticário has about 12,000 employees. As part of the SSC (Shared Services Center), I was responsible for UX improvements and interviewing users. Using ServiceNow ITSM, were created catalog items and UI components in Angular. As a facilitator of the Agile Culture, I led a Software Selection, where I analyzed agile management tools to improve the efficiency of deliveries.

# UX FRONT END DEVELOPER

OPENTECH JOINVILLE 2018 - 2019 Opentech is in the Risk Management and Logistics segment, serving medium and large customers. I started my activities working on a project that won an award in an internal competition. With that, I gained autonomy to choose React and Redux, in a new Gamification project. Our team delivered value to our customer, and we have become a reference. And that helped me to be promoted.

# MOBILE FRONT END DEVELOPER

**VALUENET** FLORIANÓPOLIS 2017 - 2018 Valuenet creates loyalty programs for large companies, through Fielo on the Salesforce platform. I joined the team as Front End Developer in 2017, where I created the documentation of the development process, as well as interfaces and components in JS, jQuery, HTML, CSS and Gulp. In 2018 I took the position of Mobile Developer and started to create applications with lonic and Angular.

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

HIPER BRUSQUE Hiper is an ERP software for store management that offers control and reporting on: sales, inventory, tax and financial. As a Full Stack Software Engineer, I worked with jQuery, CSS, PostgreSQL and C#. There I had the chance to start using Scrum as an agile methodology.

### PRODUCT MANAGER

WUP FORTALEZA 2010 - 2014 I created WUP, a startup with the mission of facilitating access to relevant information in real time. Our Social Search Engine product allowed anyone to create their own "Google" and perform simultaneous searches with indexed data from their social networks. We were selected as one of the best projects in global startup competitions.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

# SCRUM FUNDAMENTALS CERTIFIED (SFC™)

SCRUMSTUDY

## REFERENCE

### INTERVIEW ABOUT STARTUP

**STARTUPI** 2011 → LINK

#### INTERVIEW ABOUT STARTUP

JORNAL DA GLOBO 2011 → LINK

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **LEADERSHIP PROGRAM**

ONEX XP • PIB CURITIBA 2020 → LINK

#### INNOVATION AWARD

OPENTECH 2018 → LINK

#### **FINALIST**

CALL TO INNOVATION 2012 → LINK

#### **FINALIST**

LA RED INNOVA MADRID
2011 → LINK

#### **FINALIST**

DESAFIO INTEL 2011 → LINK

#### **FINALIST**

CAMPUS PARTY BRASIL 2011 → LINK

#### **CITIZENSHIP AWARD**

PROCURADORIA
GERAL DO ESTADO
2008 → LINK

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### WEB DESIGNER & DEVELOPER PROCURADORIA

GERAL DO ESTADO FORTALEZA 2008 - 2009 Analysis, creation and standardization of the interfaces of all systems. Free Software Customization, such as Drupal and Joomla, using Inkscape, Gimp, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL and PostgreSQL. Leadership in a project for Central de Licitações do Estado, that won an award in a government competition.

### PROJECT MANAGER

F7B & BRYNTEC FORTALEZA 2002 - 2017 Formerly known as Bryntec Internet Agency, F7B was created as a strategy to reach and serve customers globally by working remotely, through partnerships and outsourcing platforms. Along the way, websites, systems, apps were developed, as well as IT consultancy in the areas of UX, UI and Mobile.

## **CLIENTS**

My work is always oriented towards the success of my employers' clients, and throughout my career, I have worked hard to deliver value to some of the companies below:























